#### Contact

slholla1@texaschildrens.org

www.linkedin.com/in/shannon-holland-b22a099 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Hospitals Critical Care Nursing

# **Shannon Holland**

Director of Nursing - Critical Care at Texas Children's Houston, Texas Area

### Summary

Experienced Director of Nursing with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Performance Improvement, Clinical Research, Pediatrics, Intensive Care, and Patient Safety. Strong healthcare services professional with a MSN focused in Health Care Systems Management from Loyola University New Orleans and a DNP in Executive Leadership from the University of Texas Health Science Center in Houston.

## Experience

Texas Children's Hospital
16 years 5 months

Director of Nursing - Critical Care
October 2015 - Present (4 years 8 months)

Assistant Clinical Director PICU March 2014 - October 2015 (1 year 8 months)

Assistant Director for the Newborn Center July 2011 - March 2014 (2 years 9 months)

Nurse Manager April 2007 - July 2011 (4 years 4 months)

PICU Nurse January 2004 - April 2007 (3 years 4 months)

#### Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

DNP, Nurse Executive · (2017 - 2019)

Loyola University New Orleans

MSN, Health Care Systems Management · (2008 - 2011)

University of Louisiana at Lafayette BS, Nursing · (1999 - 2003)